#### Contact

+31643197789 (Mobile) alessandro.vozza@microsoft.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ alessandrovozza (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Cloud Computing Ceph

Linux

### Languages

Dutch (Limited Working)
English (Full Professional)
Italian (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Red Hat Certified System Administrator

OpenHack: DevOps Coach

Learning Threat Modeling for Security Professionals

AWS for Architects: High Availability and Continuous Deployment

#### **Publications**

Phosphorus ligand imaging with two-photon fluorescence spectroscopy: towards rational catalyst immobilization

Phosphorus Ligand Imaging with Two-Photon Fluorescence Spectroscopy: Towards Rational Catalyst Immobilization

# Alessandro Vozza

Software everything, public speaker, conscious coding. Amsterdam

### Summary

Experienced all-round technologist with unending passion for hard, relevant problems and their solutions. DevOps+Kubernetes+Cloud = agile continuous delivery of microservices and value. People over servers, understanding over execution, integrity over shortcut-taking. Thought leader, community enthusiast, and clearly not great at writing summaries over himself:)

## Experience

Microsoft

4 years 2 months

Principal Software Engineer September 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Amsterdam Area. Netherlands

Senior Software Engineer July 2018 - August 2019 (1 year 2 months)

Amsterdam Area, Netherlands

### **Technical Evangelist**

October 2016 - June 2018 (1 year 9 months)

Amsterdam Area, Netherlands

Sharing with partners and customers a passion for technology, people and the intersection between the two. Driving enthusiasm around Microsoft ecosystem of tools and practises, pushing the boundaries for technical excellence and fostering local tech communities and businesses to grow and scale.

Focusing on new technologies, from Blockchain to Containers passing thru

Machine Learning, AI, Bots and IoT. Long time DevOps practitioner, now helping organisations of all kinds, from startup to enterprise, to achieve more and be more lean and efficient.

The Linux Foundation

Certified Linux Foundation Trainer for CKA/CKAD (LFS458/LFS459) June 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months)

#### Amsterdam

First certified trainer in Benelux for the Linux Foundation official trainings to prepare for Certified Kubernetes Administrator and Certified Kubernetes Application Developer exams (LFS458/LFS459)

Kubernetes Community Days Amsterdam Founder

September 2019 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Amsterdam Area, Netherlands

Me and a dedicated team of community enthusiasts created from scratch the very first worldwide edition of Kubernetes Community Days in Amsterdam in September 2019, a 350-strong, developer-oriented, CNCF-backed, community-led grassroot conference.

CNCF [Cloud Native Computing Foundation]
Cloud Native Computing Foundation Ambassador
May 2018 - Present (2 years 7 months)

https://www.cncf.io/people/ambassadors/

Lovelace Engineering B.V.

Founder

October 2015 - Present (5 years 2 months)

In memory of Ada Lovelace, a great woman, a wonderful scientist, and a free thinker.

Eclipse Bookings
Artist Manager & Booking Agent
November 2015 - Present (5 years 1 month)
Amsterdam

Fresh, exciting new booking agency, true to the artist and to the art. Honoured to work with such great inspiring people!

Midi Club

Founder

October 2011 - Present (9 years 2 months)

Amsterdam Area, Netherlands

Founding member of a short-lived, but extremely intense&fresh new wave in Amsterdam techno scene. Who knows, we might reboot it soon..

DevOps Meetup Amsterdam

Founder, Organizer June 2012 - June 2017 (5 years 1 month) Amsterdam

I founded the DevOps Meetup (http://www.meetup.com/DevOpsAmsterdam/) out of curiosity and a drive to meet other professionals, to share culture and knowledge. Many people along the way have helped me, and it's really going great! We're working towards DevOps Days Amsterdam (http://devopsdays.org/events/2013-amsterdam/), join us!

ITGilde Coöperatie
Cloud Architect / Member
October 2015 - November 2016 (1 year 2 months)
Amsterdam

Namecheap, Inc Director of Cloud October 2015 - September 2016 (1 year)

Building out the cloud capability for one of the most popular registrar and web hosting provider in the world. Applying DevOps best practises to top-class infrastructure, building team culture to deploy, run and maintain a solid, reliable, scalable cloud and traditional infrastructure.

Openstack User Group Amsterdam Founder, community hacker October 2013 - June 2016 (2 years 9 months) Amsterdam

I ran the local Openstack User Group, a ~200-strong community centred around Openstack.

#### Red Hat

1 year 6 months

Senior Cloud Architect
June 2015 - October 2015 (5 months)

Grew in my role as Cloud Architect for Red Hat in Benelux, shaping and helping customers' during their journey to the cloud. Designed, architected and implemented private clouds and scalable infrastructures for several customers across a number of verticals (ISP, public sector, Telco/NFV); always bringing the value of a great culture based on openness and collaboration to multiply the effectiveness of delivery and profoundly transform the business I get in contact with. A lead-by-example position, both in my pre-sales and delivery

role, I strive to create real value for our customer and sharing my knowledge as deeply and effective as possible.

EMEA Openstack Technical Specialist May 2014 - October 2015 (1 year 6 months)

I joined Red Hat to foster my own interest in Openstack as their Specialist for the Benelux region, and to help enterprises all around EMEA to build, maintain and improve their private/hybrid clouds. This is the most exciting time to be part of such exciting organisation, to make a real impact in the "Golden Era" of cloud.

More specifically, I'll help design, spec, deploy, scale and maintain small to large sized enterprise-grade Openstack deployments, focusing on the business value and the disruption that adopting the technology and the model behind Openstack can and will bring to any kind of organisations - from startups to multi-million dollar telcos and financial institutions. Next to this, I'll keep helping growing the interest in Openstack by running local and international cloud communities, organising conferences, meet ups and user groups.

Spil Games
Head of Hosting Operations
July 2013 - April 2014 (10 months)
Hilversum

Led a team of engineers responsible for the smooth and continuous (24/7/365) operation of our multi-site portals (800+ virtual and physical servers, 180+ MAU); achieved high-availability and increased performance and agility thru directed and focused incremental improvements. Responsible for the transition from classical virtualisation (VMware) to a (private-)cloud (Openstack-based) model.

Software Improvement Group Head Of IT Operations June 2012 - July 2013 (1 year 2 months)

Organisations are completely at the mercy of their software systems. The Software Improvement Group (SIG) provides insight and analysis into the quality of software systems. We make sure you gain and retain control of your IT landscape.

We provide impartial, objective, verifiable and quantitative assessments of the structure and quality of your software systems. Our analysis software allows us to measure quality, to lay bare the underlying architecture and to assess the system. All this is done on the basis of automated source code analyses.

We make quality transparent for everyone. Whether you have a brand new client portal or a 30-year-old mainframe system, or an SAP application. Whether you are a financial institution, a logistics provider, a government agency or a high-tech service provider.

Get insight, get in control.

**Specialties** 

Software Risk Assessment, Software Portfolio Monitoring, Certification of Software Maintainability (with TÜViT), Project Risk Estimation

ID&T/Q-Dance/Sensation Sytem&Network Admin/Integrator April 2009 - April 2012 (3 years 1 month)

Revolutionized the legacy IT systems and bridge the whole business workflow into a modern, agile, efficient and secure infrastructure. Gained extensive knowledge and insight into virtualization, consolidation, service delivery and administration security and compliance. Proven record of high quality standard, excellent problem-solving skills and project management. Single-handedly restructured the IT role to align it to business goals and positively influenced the whole organization with entrepreneurial attitude and infectious spirit.

University of Amsterdam
Ph.D. program in Organic Chemistry & Spectroscopy
November 2004 - March 2009 (4 years 5 months)
Amsterdam

Joined the advanced research group of Molecular Photonics at the University of Amsterdam on a multidisciplinary project of catalysis, spectroscopy and organic synthesis. I presented poster presentations and lectures at various national and international conferences.

Note: I didn't defend my thesis yet.

Basell

Process specialist/engineer polyolefins pilot plant

January 2000 - January 2004 (4 years 1 month)

Process optimization, product research and development, plant supervision and new technologies benchmarking and start-up.

# Education

Universiteit van Amsterdam Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Chemistry · (2002 - 2009)

Università degli Studi di Ferrara M.Sc., Chemistry · (1995 - 2003)